

Berlin/Germany

□ (+49) 176 76494837 | 🔀 utku@turunc.me | 💣 utku.turunc.me | 📮 utkuturunc | 🛅 utkuturunc

Summary_

Software Engineer with system design and leading experience, creator of pet projects, freelancer

I enjoy creating value with software. I believe a good engineer must be a part of the entire process of creating software, including high level concept work, detailed technical design, implementation, deployment and maintanence. I strive to increase my existing experience on all of these fronts.

I do not have any preference between languages, components (backend/frontend) or technologies. I enjoy solving problems no matter where they are. I am always open to learning new technologies that can bring value to the project and myself.

My experience mainly consists of but not limited to high level project design, technical concept design, setting up Kubernetes clusters with Terraform, creating backends using Kotlin (ktor), Typescript (NodeJS/Express), Python (Flask) and creating frontends using Javascript/Typescript (React).

I am open for freelance projects where I can design, create and support solutions. I like to work with start-ups.

Work Experience ____

Zalando SE Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2019 - Present

- Designed and built a printing system architecture in microservices.
- Worked with Scala and Kotlin to develop logistics applications.
- Provided maintenance and support for legacy systems.

McMakler GmbH.

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Worked as a NodeJS backend engineer for in house CRM system.

Valensas Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2018

- Lead small to medium sized projects, managing communications with product and engineering teams of customers.
- Worked for a large scale banking project, designing and developing microservices
- Worked as backend engineer, focusing on chatbots.
- · Designed a chatbot framework that integrate with other web services and use machine learning and natural language processing.

Freelance Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (BACKEND/FRONTEND/DEVOPS)

Jan. 2013 - Present

- Offered services that cover the entire product pipeline, including design, management, implementation, infrastructure and deployment of projects.
- Set up kubernetes clusters for 3 different projects.
- Designed and developed: a directory of blogs webpage, truck rental and route planning app, motorcycle renting and tour reservation app, college book sharing app, donation page for a non-profit, chat based party game, online realtime fitness app.
- Supported: Al based insight generation project, implementation of a data warehouse

Skills

Programming - Strong Scala, Typescript, JavaScript, NodeJS, Kotlin, Python

Programming - Familiar Java, Spark, CoreNLP, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

Web Development ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, Express, Flask, Ktor, Play, Akka, HTML5, CSS, REST

DevOPS AWS, Google Cloud Engine, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, Linux, Microservices

Database/Cache Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Electronics SPICE, MagicVLSI, IRSIM, Matlab, Arduino, C, C++, Filter Design, VHDL, Analog Circuit Design, MEMS

Presentations

Turkey Artificial Intelligence Initiative (turkiye.ai)

Istanbul, Turkey

Presenter for Valensas Oct, 2017

• A talk about the usage of artificial intelligence in our projects

Education_

İTÜ (Istanbul Technical University) (3.95/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

• Transferred to Boğaziçi University at the end of the first year

Boğaziçi University (3.24/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

• Completed electronics specialization

· Grade is not inclusive of first year

Projects

Logistics Printing System

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ZALANDO SE

Feb. 2019 - Present

• Design and development of a large scale printing solution for logistics

Real Estate CRM System

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - McMakler GmbH.

Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

· Development and maintenance of microservices powering Immoforce, an internal CRM system for the company.

Tosla - P2P Banking Application by Akbank

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- · Developed several microservices, namely core banking and social feeds for a modern peer to peer banking application
- · Set up Kubernetes configurations and deployment pipelines.
- Project uses Spring Boot and Hibernate for core banking, Scala (Akka) for social feeds

Valensas VoT Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Jul. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Valensas VoT is a complete customizable chatbot solution that includes conversation management, natural language processing in English and Turkish, machine learning and scheduled tasks.
- Designed and developed the framework for this project that was used in several other projects.

Akbank Assistant - Akbank Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Sep. 2017 - May. 2018

- Developed a chatbot for Akbank which can be used to transfer money and pay invoices, one of the largest banks in Turkey.
- The project was written as microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to Akbank datacenters on Linux.
- Project has been released with a TV commercial and printed press coverage.

Boti - Turkish Airlines Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Developed a chatbot for Turkish Airlines, a star alliance member and flag carrier airline of Turkey. The bot can be used to buy tickets, select seats, check-in, query flight statuses and more.
- The project was written as 4 microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS.

Hepsichat - Hepsiburada Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Nov 2016 - Feb 2017

- Developed a customer support chatbot for the largest e-commerce platform in Turkey, Hepsiburada.
- The chatbot greets users, collects information and solves specific issues, if it cannot resolve the issue it redirects the users to human agents, saving time and resources.
- The project was written in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS Lambda.

AskTim - Chatbot Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2016

• Developed a Slack bot that is integrated with several analytics providers such as Mixpanel and Google Analytics.

- The bot is able to process natural language and produce visual reports combining data from different sources.
- The project was written in Scala using Play Framework and CoreNLP and deployed to AWS.

JANUARY 20, 2021 UTKU TURUNC · RÉSUMÉ